Guide to the Spears Dairy Business records, 1928-1948 MS 541
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Spears Dairy Business records
1928-1948
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Spears Dairy
MS 541
3 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Business ledgers of the Spears Dairy and its various plants and stores in Texas.
Organizational sketch
The Spears Dairy was incorporated in 1928. It was founded by the Spears family, including W. L. Spears, and served many Texas towns with dairy farms, ice cream stores, processing and distribution outlets.
Scope and Contents
Business records from Spears Dairy from the date of incorporation in 1928 to 1948. Records consist mostly of general ledgers, such as accounts receivable, accounts payable and payroll for Spears Dairy operations in several towns in Texas, inlcuding Beaumont, Giddings, La Grange, Lufkin, Port Arthur, Rosenberg, Texas City, and others. Operations included dairy farms, ice cream stores, processing and distribution outlets.
Topics include dairy farming, rural industry, rural economics.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Veronica Rutland Mallicote via the Harris County Archives, 2008.
Index Terms
Subjects
Cattle; Dairy farming; Business; Agriculture
Document Types
business records
- Series I: Business records, 1928-1948, 37835
  - Incorporation General ledger, Jan. 1,1928- Dec. 31,1928; 37858 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lufkin Ice Cream Corporation, by-Laws, minutes, stockholder ledgers March 1,1932-Jan 13,1938, 37857 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lufkin Ice Cream Store general ledger, May 1, 1942-Jan. 1,1943, 37856 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Accounts payable, Jan. 1, 1940-Dec. 31, 1940, 37855 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rosenberg general ledger, 1941-1942, 37854 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General ledger, Apr. 1, 1942- Dec 31, 1945, 37853 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Social security and withholding tax record, 1942-1944, 37852 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Farm ledger, Sept. 30, 1944-Jan. 1, 1945, 37851 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Accounts receivable, 1945, employee petty cash, social security, withholding and tax, 37850 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Accounts receivable, Jan. 1, 1946-Dec. 31, 1946, salary advances, 1946, 37849 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Accounts payable, Jan. 1, 1946-Dec. 31, 1946, 37848 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General ledger, Jan. 1, 1946-Dec. 1, 1946, Port Arthur, Houston, LaGrange, Lufkin and Rusk plants, 37847 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Accounts payable, Jan. 1, 1947- Dec. 31, 1947, 37846 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General ledger, Jan. 1, 1948-Dec. 31, 1948, 37845 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Giddings Station general ledger, Dec. 1, 1945 - Dec. 31, 1946, 37844 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Giddings journal, Nov. 1945 - Dec. 31, 1948, 37843 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Giddings General ledger, Jan 1, 1947 - Dec. 31, 1947, Accounts payable, Jan. 1, 1946 - Dec. 31, 1948, 37842 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Port Arthur plant general ledger, Jan. 1, 1946 - Dec. 31, 1946, 37841 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rusk general ledger, Jan 1, 1947 - Dec. 31, 1947, Jan. 1, 1948 - Dec. 31, 1948, 37840 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Texas City Company general ledger, Jan. 1, 1946 - Dec. 31, 1946, 37839 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Texas City company, general ledger, Jan. 1, 1947 - Dec. 31, 1947, 37838 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Orange, Spears, Rusk, dairy business ledgers, Dec. 1, 1946 - Aug. 31, 1948, 37837 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Business ledger, Jan. 1, 1946 - Dec. 31, 1946, 37836 (Box 6, Folder 2)